Guide to the Francis R. Johnson Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Francis R. Johnson papers
1932-1959
SC0286
Johnson, Francis R. (Francis Rarick), 1901-1960.
6 Linear feet
Correspondence, research notes, some biographical material, articles with notes and material relating to learned societies of which Johnson was a member. Subjects include English and American literature, Medieval science and Renaissance literature.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Mrs. Ruth Johnson, 1965, 1969.
Information about Access
Materials are open to research use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor of English at Stanford (1935-1960).
Description of the Collection
Papers include correspondence, research notes, some biographical material, articles with notes, and material relating to learned societies of which Johnson was a member. Subjects include English and American literature, Medieval science and Renaissance literature.
Access Terms
Johnson, Francis R. (Francis Rarick), 1901-1960.; Stanford University. Department of English. Faculty.; American literature --Study and teaching.; English literature--Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- Correspondence, John Butt, 1952-1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, B.E. C. Davis, 1948-1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence,George De Santillana, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, H. W. Donner, 1954-1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, Lowell M. Greenlaw and M. Y. Hughes, 1951-1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, S. Jayne and F. C. Francis, 1950-1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, ISIS, Journal of the History of Science Society and Journal of Modern History, 1955-1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, Journal of the History of Ideas and Stanford Research Institute, 1948-1959 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence: A-K, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence: L-Z, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence: A-K, 1937-1940 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence: L-P, 1937-1940 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence: R-Z, 1937-1940 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Correspondence: A-K, 1940-1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Correspondence: L-Z, 1940-1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence: A-L, 1943-1949 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Correspondence: M-Z, 1943-1949 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Correspondence: A-K, 1950-1954 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Correspondence: L-Z, 1950-1954 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence: A-GR, 1954-1959 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Correspondence: GU-M, 1954-1959 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Correspondence: Mc-Z, 1935-1958 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Correspondence: Mc-Z, 1935-1958 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, Stanford Committee on Supplementary Research Grants, 1951-1956 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, Hoyt H. Hudson [English Renaissance Prose Anthology], 1932 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Manuscripts and research notes: "Astronomy and Astrologie in Shakespeare's England" (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Manuscripts and research notes: "Did Spenser Revise the 'Shepards Calendar'?" (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Manuscripts and research notes: "Gabriel Harvey's Three Letters: A First Issue of his Fovre Letters" (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Manuscripts and research notes: "Marlowe's Imperial Heaven" and "Marlowe's Astronomy and Renaissance Skepticism" (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Manuscripts and research notes: on Robert Wyer and the printing of cheap handbooks of science in the sixteenth century (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Manuscripts and research notes: "Printers' Copy Books and the Black Market in the Elizabethan Book Trade" (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Manuscripts and research notes: "Renaissance Science" (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Manuscripts and research notes: "Scientific Spirit in Elizabethan England" and "Scientific Backgrounds of the Renaissance" (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Manuscripts and research notes: "Sir Philip Sidney as Man and Poet" (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Manuscripts and research notes: "Thomas Hood: England's First Public Teacher of the Mathematical Sciences" (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Manuscripts and research notes: "The Treatise of Erasmus De Ratione Studii, that is, Upon the Right Method of Instruction" (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Research notes: Astronomy (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
- Research notes: The Beginnings of the Teaching of Modern Subjects in England (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Research notes: Castle of Knowledge (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Research notes: Cunningham / Cosmographie (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Research notes: De Ingenuis Moribus Vergerious and Ubertinus (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Research notes: development of mathematics (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Research notes: early English poetry (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Research notes: growth of the English language (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Research notes: history written by Thucydides (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Research notes: nature and properties of wines (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Research notes: resources of Harvard Library and New York City Public Library (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Research notes: Thomas Blunderville - The Arte of Logicke (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Research notes: miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Professional organizations: History of Science Society (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Professional organizations: Institute of the History of Science (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Professional organizations: International Association of University Professors of English (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Professional organizations: International Federation for Modern Languages and Literature (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Professional organizations: Mediaeval and Renaissance Conferences (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Professional organizations: Renaissance Society of America (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Course syllabi: English Literature, History of Science, and Philosophy of Rhetoric (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Literary Reviews - various (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Literary Reviews - Hoyt Hudson (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Biographical Information: Francis Johnson (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous materials (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Subject Clippings: A-B (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Subject Clippings: C (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Subject Clippings: D (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Subject Clippings: E (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Subject Clippings: F (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Subject Clippings: G-H-I (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Subject Clippings: J-K-L (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Subject Clippings: M (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Subject Clippings: Milton (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Subject Clippings: N-O (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Subject Clippings: P-Q (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Subject Clippings: R (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Subject Clippings: S (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Subject Clippings: Shakespeare (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Subject Clippings: T (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Subject Clippings: U-Z (Box 8, Folder 7)